Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 0202. Carlisle, Lucy Percy, 1599-1660 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    Lucy Percy, Countess of Carlisle/From the original of Vandyke in the Collection of/ The Right Hon.ble The Earl of Egremont./Drawn by Satchwell & Engraved (with Permission) by E.Scriven./London. Published Oct.r 31.1816 by Lackington Allen & Co. Longman, Hurst, Rees, One and Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0203. Carlos, Infant of Spain, 1607-1632 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    Carolus Austriacus Infans./ Hispaniaruxn Films Philippi 111./Natug ammo Chr,l607. Obijt ammo Christi 1632. aetalis 25.1 Pet.PaulRubensius pinxit. Pet.de lode excudit. Right profile in oval looking right. Engraving. 14.1 x 9.1 cm.
  - 0204. Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    Carlyle./In his garden at Chelsea./Painted by Mrs. Allingham. Seated figure in oblong looking left. Etching. 33.7 x 24.4 cm.
  - 0205. Carnot, Lazare Nicolas Marguerite, comte de, 1753-1823 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    Carnot./Engraved by W.H.Mote./London. Published by Charles Knight & Co. Ludgate Street. Bust in oblong looking slightly right. Stipple-engraving. 27.2 x 17.6 cm.
  - 0206. Carracci, Annibale, 1560-1609 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    Annibal Carrache. Bust in Baroque oval looking left. Engraving. 11.5 x 8.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0207. Carter, Lawrence, bart., 18th century (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    The Honourable Sr Laurence Carter Kt./one of the Barons of his Majesties Court of Exchequer./J.Richardson pinx. G.Vertue Sculp. 1733. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 37.8 x 26.6 cm.
  - 0208. Caspars, Johann Theodor von, ?-1679 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    (hrman.Joannes Theodorun Caspans,/Serenissimo Comiti Palatino Neoburgico,/Juliae, Cliviae, ac Montium Duci etc./~ Consulijs, et ad tractatus Pacis/Universalis Legatun./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit.Corn.Galle iunior sculpsit./accessit Pnivilegium Caesareum./Cun privilegio Regun et/Hollandiae ordinum. 1649. Bust looking right in oval lettered:"Speret infestis secundis alteram sortem bene praeparatum pectus." Engraving. 30.1 x 19.6 cm, Singer No. 4815/12843. No. 85 from: Pacificatores orbis Christiani, Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 0209. Castel-Rodnigo, Francisco di Moura, 17th cent. (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    Franciscun de Moura et Corte Real Marchio/De Castel Rodrigo. Comes de Lumiares Terrceg/Novae Dominus Gubernator et Capitaneiis, Generalis haereditanius /Insularum Tercerarum Sti Georgij Faijali et Pici Magnus Comnendator/Ordinis Christi. Suae Mas.tis a Cubiculis. Eiusdemque a Consilijs Statuum/Capitaneus. Generalis Belgij. nec. non. Coniitatus Burgundiae etc. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 31.9 x 21.0 cm. Singer No. 4852/12922. No. 129 from unidentified series
  - 0210. de Mauvissire, Michel de, comte Beaumont, 1520-1592 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
    Michel de Castelnay Seigneur de Mauvissiere./Jaspar Isac fecit. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Under portrait: "L'obiect de ce portraict fera, veoir au Lecteur/ du visage lea traicts bien formez de Lauteur/mais son esprit divin cogneu en son histoire/Luy fera beaucoup plus estimer sa memoire."
  - 0211. Castiglione, Baldassare, conte, 1478-1529 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Portrait du Comte Balthasar Castiglione/d'apès le tableau de Raphael, qui eat dams le Cabinet du Roy./haut de 29.pouces, large de 24.pouces, grave par Nicolas Edelinck. Half-portrait turned slightly to the right. Engraving. 24.3 x 18.0 cm. Singer No. 4853/12929.
  - 0212. Catarina Cornaro, queen of Cyprus, 1454-1510 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Catharina Cornara,/Regina Cypri, Jacobi II. Regis vidua./Titian pinx. G.L.f. Knee-piece looking right. Engraving. 19.0 x 14.0 cm.
  - 0213. Catherine of Aragon, queen of England, 1485-1536 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Catherine of Aragon, Queen of K.Henry VIII./In the Collection of the Hon.ble Horace Walpole./Holben pinxit. J.Houbraken sculps. Mist. 1743./Impensis J. & K.Knapton. Londini 1744. From: Birch, V. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J.Knapton, London, 1743. Bust in lettered oval looking right, surrounded by Baroque composition. Engraving. 36.9 x 24.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0214. Catherine Howard, queen of England, 1520-1542 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Catherine Howard. Queen of K.Henry VIlI/Jacobus Houbraken sculpsit Mist. Holben Pinx.i in the Collection of Mr. Richardson. From: Birch,T. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J.Knapton, London, 1743. Bust in lettered oval looking right surrounded by Baroque composition. Engraving. 36.2 x 23.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. SSinger No. 4881/12998
  - 0215. Catherine de Medici, queen of [Henri II] France, 1519-1589 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Catherine de Medicis Queen of France./J.Chapman sculpsit. London. Published as the Act directs. Decr. 23. 1804. by J.Wilkes. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.4 cm
  - 0216. Catinat, Nicolas de La Fauconnire de, 1637-1712 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Nicolas de Catinat Marechal de France./C,Vermeulen sculpsit et ex. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Engraving. 44.5 x 33.3 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 4886/13039.
  - 0217. Cavaceppi, Bartolomeo, 1716-1799 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Bartolomeo Cavaceppi Romano Scultore/e Ristauratore delle Statue antiche. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 35.7 x 23.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Foxed.
  - 0218. Celtes Conradun, 1459-1508 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Conradus Celtes Protucius,/P.L.C. et Prof. Vienn./nat. d. 1. Febr.1459. den. d. 3. Febr. 1508./Joh. Jac. Haid excud. Aug. Vind. Bust in oval looking slightly left. Mezzotint. 21.5 x 14.5 cm. Singer No. 23790/72320.
  - 0219. Cenci, Beatrice, 1577-1599 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Beatrice Cenci./A Sua Altezza it Margravio/Carlo Leopoldo Federico di Baden/Arturia e Fontaine fl.D.D./Mannheim presso Artaria e Fontaine./Felsing impresse./Guido Reni dip. T.Minard dis.Giovita Garavaglia incise. Bust in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 32.3 x 24.0 cm.
  - 0220. Chabot, de St. Maurice, Claude, marquis de Savoy, 17th cent. (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
    Claudius de Chabot./Marchio Sancti Mauritij, Eques Torquatun Ordinis/Divae Mariae Annuntiatae, Rei Tormentariae Sereniss'mi/Sabaudiae Ducis Generalis Praepositus, Suae Regiae Celsitudinis Praetorianorum Praefectun, Campi Narescallun Genera/lis in omnibus eius exercitibus, et ad Tractatus Pacis Uni/versalis eiusdem Regiae Celsnis nomine Legatus Plenipot.rius. etc/ accessit Privilegium Caesarum. Cun privilegio Regum et Hollandiae Ordinun. Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Paul Pontiun sculpsit. 1648. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Vanae in virtutem insidiae". Engraving. 31.1 x 19.8 cm. Singer No. 4971/13243. No. 77 from: Celebernimi ad pacificandum. Chnistiani nominis orbem Legati, Monasterium et Osnabrugas... Anvers, 1648.
  - 0221. Chaloner, Sir Thomas, ca 1640 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Sir Thomas Chaloner./In the Common Parlour at Houghton./Size of the Picture.. ./Van Dyke Pinxit. Geo.Farington delin. Richard Earlom sculpsit./Published March 2nd 1778, by John Boydell Engraver in Cheapside London. Bust in oblong looking left. Mezzotint. 41.5 x 30.1 cm. Singer No. 4979/13264.
  - 0222. Chambers, Sir William, 1726-1796 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Sir Wn.Chambers./ W.Bromley Sculp. 1792. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Engraving. 13.8 x 10.4 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0223. Champaigne, Philippe de, 1602-1674 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Philippus de Champaigne Bruxellensis Pictor Regius, et Regiae Pictorum Academiae Rector/Eximiae hujun arts excel1enti~, et christiang pietate oeque insignis./Se ipse pinxit. G.Edelinck sculpsit 1676. Cum. pri. R. Half-portrait in oblong landscape looking right. Scroll lettered 1668 in right hand. Engraving. 39.0 x 31.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 4994/13296.
  - 0224. Chandler, Edward, bp. of Durham, 18th cent. (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Reverendus admodum Edwardus Chandler/Dunelmensis Episcopus/Consecrat 1730./ J.Vanderbank pinxit. Geo. Vertue Sculpsit 1738. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 35.8 x 25.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0225. Chandler, Edward, bp. of Durham, 18th cent. (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
  - 0226. Chappe, d'Auteroche, Jean, Abb., 8th cent. (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    L’Abbé Chappe./Fredou pinx. Tilliard sculpa. Bust in oval looking left in oblong. Engraving, 26.5 x 18.6 cm. Singer No. 5005/13316.
  - 0227. Chapelle, Claude Emmanuel Lhullier, 1626-1686 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Cde. E.el Luillier Surn,é Chapelle/Né en 1626. mort en l686./C.le Brim pinx. Ingouf Jun. Sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 17.7 x 11.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0228. Chardin, Sir John, 1643-1713 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Johannes Chardin Mlles./Natus 6/16 novembris 1643. D.Loggan ad Vivum sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 26.5 x 16.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0229. Charles [son of Charles VIII] dauphin of France, 1496-? (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Carolus Orlandus Delp. Fr. Caroli VIII Re. F./Charles Orland X Dauphin de Fr./ I.Fils du Roy/Charles VIII/de son Tontheau/ a S.Martin de Tours. Bust in lettered circle looking right over composition with dolphins. Engraving. 19.7 x 13.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0230. Charles the Great, Holy Roman emperor, 742-814 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
    Charlenagne./J.Chapman sculp./London, publish'd as the Act directs. Jan. 18. 1805 by J.Wilkes. Left profile in oval. Coronation in oblong below. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0231. Charles I, king of Great Britain, 1600-1649 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Carols Rex Angliae./R.Gaywood fecit. Bust in oval looking right. Etching. 14.4 x 9.9 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0232. Charles I, king of Great Britain, 1600-1649 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    King Charles the First,/Obt. XXX Jan. 1648./From an exellent Original in the Royal Palace of Hampton Court./Ant.Vandyke Eques pinx. Ceo. Vertue scuip. From: Birch, T. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J.Knapton, London, 1756. Bust in window looking slightly right. Royal insignia in lower center. Engraving. 29.8 x 19.0 cm. Singer No. 5017/13384.
  - 0233. Charles I, king of Great Britain, 1600-1649 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Charles I King of England and C./R.Gaywood fecit. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Etching. 14.3 x 8.1 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0234. Charles I, king of Great Britain, 1600-1649 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Charles I.r. Roy d'Angleterre./Wan der Werff pinxit. Ben.Audran sculpsit. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 31.5 x 18.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0235. Charles II, king of Great Britain, 1630-1685 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Carols II. dux D. G. Ang. Sco. Fra. et Hib. Rex Fidei Defensor and C./G.Kneller pinx. J.Smith fee. et ex. Bunt in oval looking slightly right. Mezzotint. 19.6 x 14.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0236. Charles II, king of Great Britain, 1630-1685 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Charles II./King of England, Scotland, France & Ireland,/Defender of the Faith & c./ From a Picture in Bridewell Hall, London the Original painted by Sr. Peter Lely Kt. Geo. Vertue Sculp. 1736. Bust in fancy oval looking left. "Mon Dieu et Droit" in band surrounding it. Engraving. 30.6 x 19.7 cm.
  - 0237. Charles II, king of Great Britain, 1630-1685 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Carolus II. D. G. Mag. Brit. Fran. & Hiber: Rex. & etc./R.White sculpsit. Standing full portrait in oblong. Engraving. 48.2 x 27/9 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 5o18/13481.
  - 0238. Charles Edward Lewis Philip Casimir, prince of England, 1720-1788 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Bust in oblong looking right. Four quatrains of eulogy under it. Mezzotint. 29.2 x 20.2 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Tocque, Louis, 1696-1772. French.
  - 0239. Charles V, king of France, 1337-1380 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Charles V.fdit/le Sage/N.Pin. de Marcenay Sculp. 1767./A Paris chéz l’Auteur rue d’Anjou Dauphine,/et chëz Mr.Wille Graveur du Roi Quay des Gr.Augustins./P1. No.2 de l’oeuvre./M.le Marquis de Brancas a bien voulu communiquer le Portrait a 1’Auteui. Left profile in oblong; under portrait: "Que de jours perdus, François, pour la Partie./Ces jours. qu’un poison lent retrancha de sa vie,/Forme par’les malheurs au grand art de regner./Charles cinq avoit açu par sea soins raniner/L’amour du bien public éteint dams l’Anarchie;/Moderer les Impots, protéger l’industrie:/Sage enfin, oeconome, actif et liberal/Il avoit subjuqud son orqueilleux Vassal.” Stipple-engraving.15.3 x 9.8 cm. Singer No. 5021/13612. a. -
  - 0240. Charles VII, king of France, 1403-1461 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
    Charles VII. of France/J.Chapman sculpt./London. Published as the Act directs Novr. 23rd 1805 by J. Wilkes. Left profile in oval. King enthroned with priest and warrior in oblong below. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0241. Charles VIII, king of France, 1470-1498 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Charles VIII, of France./ J.Chapman sculpt./London. Published as the Act directs. May 1st. 1805, by J.Wilkes. Right profile in oval. Equestrian preceded by torch-bearers and followed by a warrior with the colors in oblong below. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0242. Charles XI, king of France, 1550-1574 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Charles IX. of France./J.Chapman sculpt./London Published as the Act directs. Oct 12d 1805. by J.Wllkes. Left profile in oval with battle scene in oblong below. Stipple-engraving. 16.0 x 11.0 cm.
  - 0243. Charlotte [Augusta of Great Britain, duchess Leopold of Sachsen Coburg Gotha], queen of Leopold I of Belgium, 1796-1817 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    The Princess Charlotte./Painted by Sir Tho.s Lawrence Principal Painter in Ordinary to his Majesty by President of the Royal Academy,/Engraved by Richard Golding./ To his most excellent Majesty, George the Fourth, King of Great Britain/This Engraving from the original Picture painted in October 1817, is with His gracious permission humbly dedicated. /Published January 1st 1822 by Messrs Colnaghi & Co Cockspur Street. By his Majesty's dutiful subjects & servants,/Co]~naghi. Standing knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 52.4 x 35.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 5036/13778.
  - 0244. Chateaubriand, Francois August, 1768-1848 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Chateaubriand,/Waltner del et sculp./Publi~ par Defour, Mulat et Boulanger./Imp.e Guilquin et Dupain r. de la Calandre 19, Paris. Bust looking left. Lithograph. 27.4 x 17.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0245. Chaucer, Geoffrey, 1328-1400 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Geoffrey Chaucer./In the Collection of Sir Hans Sloane Bart./J.Houbraken scuips. Amst. 1741./ Impensis I. & P.Knapton Londini 1742. From: Birch, T. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J. & P.Knapton, London, 1743. Bust in lettered oval looking right with symbolic composition in lower center. Engraving. 37.5 x 23.9 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 5086/13933.
  - 0246. Chaucer, Geoffrey, 1328-1400 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Geoffrey Chaucer./J.Collyer sculp. Bust in oval looking left.Engraving. 16.5 x 11.3 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0247. Chaulieu, Guilleaume Amf rye de, 1636?-1720 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Chaulieu. /Deveria del. /A.Jehotte, sculp. Bust in small oval, looking slightly right.Stipple-engraving.21.0 x 12.3 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark. Slightly foxed.
  - 0248. Chauveau, Francois, 1613-1676 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Francois Chauveau./Graveur ordinaire du Roy./Le febrvre pinxit. Edelinck scuip. C.P.R. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Engraving.26.2 x 18.7 cm.Singer No. 5093/13953.
  - 0249. Cheke, Sir John, 1514-1557 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    Joannes Checus Eques Auratus Lingua Grae. Profes./Ingenium magni moderatus Principis exul./Checus at inconstans in Frietate Fuit. AB./Engraved by T.Berry/Fron the Original in the Heroologia./Published by T.Rodd, 2, Ct. Newport Street, Long Acre. Bust in lettered oval looking left. Engraving. 19.1 x 11.7 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0250. Chenier, Marie Joseph de, 1764-1811 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
    M.J.Chénier./Né a Constantinople, le 28 Aout 1764.! mort ~ Paris le 10 Janvier 1811.! Imp. de Ducarme./Galérie Universelle. Publie par Blaiset./No. 48. Unframed bust looking right. Lithograph.25.7 x 21.6 cm.
  - 0251. Chicheley, John Richard, 17th century (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Sir Richard Chicheley. /Admiral/under Prince Rupert. /R.Dunkarton Sculpt. Bust in oblong looking right.Mezzotint.28.9 x 20.7 cm.
  - 0252. Chiverton, sir Richard, 17th century (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Sir Richard Chiverton./Lord Mayor of London/Anno 1657. London. Published by S.Woodburx 1814. R.Dunkarton Sculp.t. Bust in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 28.8 x 20.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0253. Choiseul du Plessis-Praslin, Gilbert de, bp. of Comminges (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Gilbertus de Choiseul Consiliarius Regis in eis Consiliis et Espiacopus comingensis. Bust in octagonal frame looking left. Engraving.29.5 x 23.3 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0254. Christian, duke of Braunschweig, bp., 1599-1626 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Christiano D.G.Postulato Ep.o Halberstadieusi,/Duci Brunsvicensi, et Luneburgensi Etc.! Ant. van Dyck pinxit. Robertus van Voerst sculpsit.Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Half-portrait in oblong looking right.Engraving.24.1 x 17.6 cm.Singer No. 5225/14554.Dutuit No. 198. 2e.Mauquoy-H. No. 186.11. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0255. Christophorus Patavinus, 1500-1569 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Christophorus Patavinus, Philosophus at Theologus eximius, floruit in/Concilio Tridentino. obiit Romae non sine sanctitatis opinione 1569. Cum Ordinem Erem. S. Aug. an. 18 felicissime gubernasset. [I. Fran. in.] Bust in oval looking left, surrounded by Baroque frame-work.Engraving.13.3 x 10.0 cm.
  - 0256. Cibber, Theophilus, 1703-1758 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Cibber. !A. Bannerman Sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving.18.8 x 13.7 cm.
  - 0257. Clairaut, Alexis Claude, 1713-1765 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Clairaut,/C.N.Cochin del. Cathelin sculp. Right profile in oval, in oblong.Engraving.26.7 x 18.7 cm. Singer No. 5349/15160.
  - 0258. Clarendon, Edward Hyde, 1st earl of, 1609-1674 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Edward Hyde, Earl of Clarendon./From the original of Sir Peter Lely, in the Collection of/The Right Hon.ble The Earl of Clarendon./Drawn by Wm.Hilton, R.A. & Engraved (with Permission) by R.Cooper./London, Published Sept. 29. 1820. by Lackington, Hughes, Harding, Mayor & Jones and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orine & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking left.Stipple-engraving.37.2 x 26.4 cm.Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 0259. Clarke, Samuel, 1675-1729 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Samuel Clarke D.D./In the possession of Mrs. Clarke.!Gibson pinxit. J.Houbraken sculps. Amst.!Impensis 3. & P. Knapton. Londini. Bust in lettered oval looking right.Engraving.36.7 x 23.2 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0260. Claudius Drusus Nero Germanicus, Tiberius, 5th emperor of Rome, 10-54 A.D. (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
    Claudius,/born at Lions in Gaul/reign'd 13th Years, 8 Months, 20 Days,i'was poyson'd in ye Year of/Christ 54. Left profile in oval lettered:"Ti. Claudius Caesar Aug. Germ. P.M. Tr.P."Engraving.18.2 x 11.1 c;.Plate-mark trimmed partly off.Illustration: "Vol. XIX page 324" from unidentified book.
  - 0261. Claudius Drusus Nero Germanicus, Tiberius, 5th emperor of Rome, 10-54 A.D. (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Dru. Caludius Tib. Caesar, Fils de Druse et Oncle de Caligule. Regna 13 ans 9 mois.Cestuy cy fut un monstre d'homes,/qui preposa Neron a son propre fils.. .Mariette excud. Sueton en Cl. Right profile in oblong.Engraving.28.1 x 19.1 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.From an unidentified edition of Suetonius Tranquillius. Histoire des douze Cesars.
  - 0262. Claudius Drusus Nero Germanicus, Tiberius, 5th emperor of Rome, 10-54 A.D. (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Ti.Claudius Caesar. Aug. P.M. Yr. P. Imp. P.P./V.Right profile in lettered circle. Over portrait:"Nit auff die selbige weiss gehoertman sich vor. em yb und vor em wild thier zu huten." under portrait:"Seines alters 60. jar, und im 14. seiner regierung, hatmen im mit toedlichen gift das leben auss getrieben." Engraving.24.3 x 20.7 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark. No. 5 from unidentified German version of Suetonius T.: Vita XII. Caesarum.
  - 0263. Claviare, Etienne, 1753-1793 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    E.Claviere,/franz6sischer Finanz Minister./1793./J.F.Bolt Sc: Juny 93. Bust in oval looking right.Stipple-engraving.12.7 x 8.2 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 5398/15276.
  - 0264. Clemens IX, [Giulio Rospigliosi], 1599-1669 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Clement, IXe, du Nom, Pape, Crée/en cette Suprae Dignité le 20e, de Juin 1667. Ilest/Age de 68 ans./Natif de Pistoia en Toscane; cy devant étoit nommé/Jule CardinalRospigliosi; Il ~ fait les Card. aux Ottobiiono,/Dattaire et le Cardinal AzzolinoSecretaire d'Estat;/A Paris chez P.Berbiand. Rue St Jacques a la poinme d'Or pres StSeverin. Avec Pri.e du Roy./De Larmessin-Sculebat 1. Bust in oval looking left.Engraving.22.8 x 16.4 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0265. Clermont-Tonnerre, Francois count, bp. of Noyon, 1629-1701 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    [Francois de Clermont Tonnerre, evaque comte de Noyon.] Nanteuil ad vivum faciebat1655. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving.32.0 x 24.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 5438/15561.
  - 0266. Cleve, Cornelis van, 1645-1732 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Corneil van Cleve./Sculpteur ord.re du Roy, Ancien Directeur;/et ajoint a Recteur, en son Academie Royale./Peint par J.Vivien. Grave par J.B.Poilly pour sa/Réception a 1' l'Academie en 1714. Bust in oval looking left.Engraving.35.3 x 24.7 cm.Plate-mark trimmed of f. Singer No. 5448/15581.
  - 0267. Cleve, Joos van, 1515?-1554? (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Joas van Cleeve. J.Miller sculp. Bust in oblong looking left.Engraving.18.0 x 14.1 cm
  - 0268. Clovis, king of the Franks, 466-511 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Clovis. /The First Christian King of France. /J. Chapman s culp. /London, Published as the Act directs, April 19th 1806, by J.Wilkes. Left profile in oval. Worshiping figure and warriors in oblong below.Stipple-engraving.16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0269. Cnollen, Adolph Andreas, 1674-1714 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Adam. Andr. Cnollaeius/Diac. Eccl. Furt. Simbol. Ps. 84.6. Bust in oval looking right in oblong.Engraving.13.6 x 8.7 cm.Fragment clipped out from larger print.
  - 0270. Cocceji, Heinrich von, 1644-1719 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
    Heinricus a Coccejus/Regiae Maj. Borruss. a Consiliis intimis:/in Academ. Viadrina Ordinarius/et Antecessor Primarius./Bernigeroth Sc. C.Mflller pinx. Engraving.27.2 x 17.3 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.Singer No. 5490/15793.
  - 0271. Coccejus [Cock], Johannes, 1603-1669 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8)
    Coccejus./W. de Broen Excudit. Bust in oval looking right.Engraving.30.0 x 20.0 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0272. Coccejus [Cock], Johannes, 1603-1669 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8)
    Johannes Cocceius/In Academia Lugduno-Batava S. Theobogiae Professor. J. de Vos pinxit. 1652. J.Snijderhoef scuipsit. C.Banheijnigh excudit. Bust in oblong looking right.Engraving.30.7 x 22.8 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.Singer No. 5493/15823.
  - 0273. Coch, Gerhard, 17th cent. (Flat-box 2, Folder 8)